So, let's keep this our base case.
所以这是我们的基准情形
We have a long term memory which is at
我们有个长期记忆
the show we're watching it's about nature and science.
即记得我们看的节目是关于自然和科学的
We also have a short term memory which is what we've recently seen,
还有个短期记忆 即我们最近看到的内容
a squirrel and a tree.
也就是一只松鼠和一棵树
And finally, we have our current event which is a picture we
最后 我们还有当前事件 也就是一张我们刚看到的图片
just saw that looks like a dog but it could also be a wolf.
有点像只狗 但也有可能是头狼
So let's study the learn gate.
我们来研究学习门
What the learn gate does is the following.
学习门要做的是
It takes a short term memory and the event and it joins it. Actually, it does a bit more.
取短期记忆和事件 将两者合并 实际上 它做的不止这些
It takes the short term memory and the event and it combines
它会接受短期记忆和事件 将两者合并起来
them and then it ignores a bit of it keeping the important part of it.
然后忽略其中的一部分 只保留重要的部分
So here it forgets the fact that there's a tree and it
所以这里它忘了有棵树
remembers how we recently saw a squirrel and a dog/wolf.
只记得我们最近看到了一只松鼠和一条狗/一只狼
And how does this work mathematically?
这背后的数学原理是什么呢？
Well, it works like this. We have the short term memory STMt minus
是这样的 我们有短期记忆 STMt-1
one and the event Et and it combines them by putting them through
和事件 Et 学习门会把它们合并起来 也就是把它们代入一个
a linear function which consists of joining the vectors multiplying by
线性函数里 也就是把两个向量放到一起
a matrix adding a bias and finally squishing the result with a tanh activation function.
然后乘以一个矩阵 再加一个偏差 最后将所得结果代入 tanh 激活函数里
Then the new information Nt has this form over here.
然后新信息 Nt 就产生了 它的结构就是这样
Now, how do we ignore part of it?
那我们要怎么忽略其中一部分呢？
Well, by multiplying by an ignore factor, I-T.
我们可以将其乘以一个遗忘因子 it
The ignore factor, I-T,
遗忘因子 it
is actually a vector but it multiplies element wise.
实际上是一个向量 但它可以像元素一样进行乘法运算
And how do we calculate I-T?
要怎么计算 it 呢？
Well, we use our previous information of the short term memory and the event.
这就要用到短期记忆和事件以前的信息了
So again, we create a small neural network
所以 我们要再次创建一个小型神经网络
whose inputs are the short term memory and the event.
其输入为短期记忆和事件
We'll pass them through a small linear function with a new matrix and
把它们代入一个小型线性函数里 在函数里乘以一个新矩阵
a new bias and squish them with the sigmoid function to keep it between zero and one.
再加一个新偏差 把所得结果代入 sigmoid 函数 使其值保持在 0 和 1 之间
So that's it. That's how the learn gate works.
就是这样了 这就是学习门的工作原理